Finding Aid for the The Donald Grady Davidson Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Writings
  - Book Manuscripts
    - Big Ballad Jamboree, Chapters IX - XXI, original typed MS (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Big Ballad Jamboree, Photocopy Chapters 1 - 5 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Big Ballad Jamboree, Photocopy Chapters 6 - 8 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Big Ballad Jamboree, Photocopy Chapters 9 - 11 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Big Ballad Jamboree, Photocopy Chapters 12 - 16 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Big Ballad Jamboree, Photocopy Chapters 17 - 19 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Big Ballad Jamboree, Photocopy Chapters 20 -21 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Chapters from Divided We Stand which was published as Attack on Leviathan (Box 19, Folder 6 -23)
    - Divided We Stand. Contents. (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Divided We Stand. The Nation We Are. (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Divided We Stand. The Nation We Are. (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Divided We Stand. Regionalism in the Arts. (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Divided We Stand. Regionalism in the Arts. (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Divided We Stand. Chapters from The American Review. (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Divided We Stand. The Immovable Bodies. (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Divided We Stand. Political Economy of Regionalism. (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Divided We Stand. Regionalism and Nationalism in American Literature. (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Divided We Stand. American Heroes (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Divided We Stand. Howard Odum and the Sociological Proteus. (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Divided We Stand. Where Regionalism and Sectionalism Meet reprint from Social Forces Vol. 13, No. 1, October 1934 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Divided We Stand. Fragments. (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Divided We Stand. The Dilemma of the Southern Liberals, No. 1 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Divided We Stand. The Dilemma of the Southern Liberals No. 2 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Divided We Stand. The Dilemma of the Southern Liberals (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Divided We Stand. The Dilemma of the Southern Liberals (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Divided We Stand. The Dilemma of the Southern Liberals reprint from The American Mercury, Feb. 1934 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Lee in the Mountains and Other Poems. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Lee in the Mountains and Other Poems. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - The Long Street No. 1 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - The Long Street No. 2 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - The Long Street No. 3 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - The Long Street No. 4 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - The Long Street No. 5 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - The Long Street No.6 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - The Long Street No. 7 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - The Long Street, Book Manuscript (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Readings for Composition, No. 1 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Readings for Composition, No. 2 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Readings for Composition, No. 3 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Readings for Composition, No. 4 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Readings for Composition, No. 5 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Readings for Composition, No. 6 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Readings for Composition, No. 7 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Readings for Composition, No. 8 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Readings for Composition, No. 9 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Readings for Composition, No. 10 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Southern Writers in the Modern World. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - The Tall Men No.1 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - The Tall Men No.2 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - The Tall Men No.3 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - The Tall Men No.4 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - The Tall Men No.5 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - The Tall Men (Incomplete final drafts) No. 6 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - The Tall Men (Incomplete final drafts) No. 7 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - The Tall Men (Incomplete final drafts) No. 8 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - The Tall Men (Rough drafts) No. 9 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - The Tall Men (Rough drafts) No. 10 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - The Tall Men (Rough drafts) No. 11 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - The Tall Men (Rough drafts) No. 12 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - The Tall Men (Rough drafts) No. 13 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - The Tall Men (Rough drafts) No. 14 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - The Tall Men (Rough drafts) No. 15 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - The Tall Men (Rough drafts) No. 16 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - The Tall Men (Rough drafts) No. 17 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1, Three Woodcuts by Theresa Sherrer Davidson (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. I (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - The Tennessee, Vol.1 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - The Tennessees,Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 1 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2, No. 26 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2, No. 27 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2, No. 28 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2, No. 29 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - The Tennessee, Vol. 2, No. 30 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - The Tennessee, Table of Contents and Chapter 1 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - The Tennessee. First Comers. Chapter 2. (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - The Tennessee. The River of the Cherokees. Chapter 3. (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - The Tennessee. Myths and Games of the Cherokees. Chapter 4. (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - The Tennessee. The Carolina Traders and Their Empire. Chapter 5. (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - The Tennessee. The Brilliant Idea of a Scottish Baronet. Chapter 6. (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - The Tennessee. The Siege and Fall of Fort Loudoun. Chapter 7. (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - The Tennessee. Fort Loudoun, Monument of Lost Empire. Chapter ? (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - The Tennessee. Rally in the Canebrake. Chapter 10. (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - The Tennessee. Rally in the Canebrake. Fragment. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - The Tennessee. John Sevier and the Lost State of Franklin. Chapter 12 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - The Tennessee. Dragging Canoe Blockades the River. Chapter 13. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - The Tennessee. Flatboat and Keelboat Days. Chapter 14. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - The Tennessee. Boatmen and Outlaws on the Trace. Chapter 15. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - The Tennessee. Early Steamboat Days. Chapter 16. (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - The Tennessee. Selected Bibliography (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Misc. pages from The Tennessee No. 1 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Misc. pages from The Tennessee No. 2 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Misc. pages from The Tennessee No. 3 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Untitled. "South Carolina MS Book and Notes" (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Untitled. " South Carolina MS Book and Notes" -Chronology-Montgomery's expedition against Cherokees (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - South Carolina Book and Notes "Fort Loudoun: the Years of Decision" (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Articles, Essays, and Lectures
    - "About Merrill Moore" (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - "An Agrarian Looks at the New Deal" (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - "The Agrarian South: An Interpretation" (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - "The Agrarians Today" Shenandoah Summer 1952, Vol. III, No. 2 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - "The Agrarian Tradition: Resume of Principles" (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - "The All Day Singing at Cedar Valley" (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - "Allen Tate: The Traditionalist as Modern" (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - "Aristocracy and Machinery" (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - "Articles of an Agrarian Reform " (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - "Articles of an Agrarian Restoration" (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - "The Artist as Southerner." In Saturday Review, May 15, 1926 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - "The Artist as Southerner." (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - "The Average Man and Poetry (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - "At the Railway Station, Middlebury, July 19, 1949" (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - "Die Bedeutung der Sudstaaten in der Modernen Amerikanischen Literatur" (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - " Brother Jonathan and Cousin Roderick" (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Commencement Address-Breadloaf School of English, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Commencement Address --Breadloaf School of English, 1956 32) Commencement Address-Breadloaf School of English (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Commencement Address-Peabody Demonstration School, June 5, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Commencement Address-Wallace School (no date) (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - The Communion of the Ever-Living: A Statement of the Role of the Humanities (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - "Counterattack, 1930 -1940: The South Against Leviathan" delivered as the second lecture in the Eugenia Dorothy Blount Lamar Memorial Lectures, Nov. 1957 at Mercer University (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - "Counter-Revolution: The Sequel to I'll Take My Stand (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - "The Crisis in Education" (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - "Criticism Outside New York" (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - "Current Attitudes Toward Folklore" (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - Dominance of Government over Culture. Nationalism in the Industrial Age. (Box 24, Folder 41)
    - " Dying Cities, Living Fields" (Box 24, Folder 42)
    - "Economics and Life" (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Edna Ferber's So Big (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - "Education for Quality" (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - "The English Teacher and the Lost Humanities" No. 1 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - " " " No. 2 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - " " " No. 3 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - "Erskine Caldwell's Picture Book" (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Essays on Liberals (untitled) (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - "An Exhortation for the Times " (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - "Faulkner e Warren" (in Portuguese) (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - "Faulkner and Warren: A Study in the Vitality of Tradition" (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - "Faulkner and Warren: A Note on the Role of the South in Contemporary American Literature" (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - "First Fruits of Dayton" (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - "The Folk in Literature" (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - "Folkways and Folk Arts" (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Foreword. The Works and Days of Arthur Palmer Hudson. (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Foreword and Notes. The Southern Tradition at Bay, by Richard Weaver. (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - "Geography of the Brain" (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - "Grammar and Rhetoric: The Teacher's Problem,", 1953 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - "Grammar and Rhetoric: The Teacher's Problem" (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - "Grand Tour at Age 72 or The New "Innocents Abroad" Autumn, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - "The Great Plains" (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - "Gulliver Goes South" (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - "Gulliver with Hay Fever." (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - "History of the Honor System at Vanderbilt" (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - "The Horrors of Peace" (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - I'll Take My Stand-Dedication and Prospectus (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - "In Memory of John Gould Fletcher" (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - " Introduction to the Fugitive,", 1966 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - " Introduction to John Donald Wade's Essays" (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - "Introduction: A Statement of Principles" No. 1 (I'll Take My Stand) (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - " " No. 2 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - " " No. 3 (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - "Introduction to Voltmeier" by William Gilmore Simms (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - " John Dos Passos-No Rip Van Winkle" (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - " John Dos Passos-No Rip Van Winkle" (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - "Joseph Conrad's Directed Indirections" (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - " Joseph Conrad's Directed Indirections." The Sewanee Review, April 1925 (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - " Joseph Conrad and the Vision of His Youth" (lecture) (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - " Kennedy's Horseshoe Robinson: A Tale of the Tory Ascendancy "( 1835) (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - "Kennedy's Rob of the Bowl," 1838 42) Kennedy's Swallow Barn or a Sojourn in the Old Dominion (1832) (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - " John Pendleton Kennedy (1795 - 1870)" (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - Kingdom Coming. (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - Kingdom Coming. Muscle Schoals and the T. V. A. (Box 25, Folder 45)
    - Kingdom Coming. Muscle Schoals. The Flint Rocks, and TVA. (Box 25, Folder 46)
    - "Lands That Were Golden" (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Lecture on Southern Literature (untitled) (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Lecture on Southern Writers, pp. 10 - 16 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - " Literature as Experience and Form" (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - "The Local Color Novel" (Creative Reading, Sept. 15, 1928, Vol. II, No. 23) (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - "The Lyric of the 1600's: Song or Poem?" (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - "The Lyric of Tradition" (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - "The Machine Age" (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Mark Twain (lecture) (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - " The Master of the Sacred Harp: In Memoriam George Pullen Jackson, 1874 - 1953" (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - " " (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - "Medieval Lyrics: The Poem As Song" (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - " A Meeting of Southern Writers" (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - " Middletown, Yankee Town, and Rebelville." (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - "A Mirror for Artists " No. 1 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - "A Mirror for Artists" No. 2 (from I'll Take My Stand) (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - " The ‘Mystery' of the Agrarians" (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - " Nashville in the Eighteen- Nineties" (Coffee House Club, Feb. 16, 1967) (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - " (carbon copy) (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - " The New South and Conservatism" (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - " " (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - The New South and the Conservative Tradition (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - " " (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - " " (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - "No Ammer " (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - "Not Quite Yankees-Still More Rebels " (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - The Old Oak Club, 1888-1938 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - " On Teaching Democracy Through Literature" (2 copies) (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - " " (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Peabody Radio Round Table, 1940 (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - Poetry and Progress; Poetry as Tradition (2 copies) (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - The Political Economy of Regionalism (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - Political Regionalism and Administrative Regionalism (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - " Pre-Admission Acquaintance with the Honor System" (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - "Preface to Decision" (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - " " (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - "Preface to Decision (A Study of the Race Problem" Nashville Banner, 9-7-45) (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - "Preliminary Discussion - Southern Letters - 1931" (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - " Pullin' Corn: A New Georgia Scene. (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - Quotations from I'll Take My Stand (Box 26, Folder 40)
    - "Recollections of Robert Frost" (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - " The Recrudescence of Kipling." (Box 26, Folder 42)
    - " Regionalism" (Box 26, Folder 43)
    - " " (Box 26, Folder 44)
    - " " (includes letter to W. T. Couch, 1953) (Box 26, Folder 45)
    - " " (Box 26, Folder 46)
    - " " (Box 26, Folder 47)
    - Regionalism. Notes (Legal size folder) (Box 26, Folder 48)
    - "Regionalism in College English Courses" (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - "Regionalism in Modern American Literature" No. 1 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - " " No. 2 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - " " No. 3 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - " Regionalism Versus Chaos" (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - " Relationship of the Faculty and Administrative Officers to the Honor System" (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - " Remarks Given at the Installation of Alexander Heard as Chancellor of Vanderbilt University 1963." (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Remarks Given at Memorial Assembly for Elizabeth Drew. Bread Loaf School of English. (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - "The Renaissance of Southern Poetry and Literature" (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - A Reply to Clarence Cason's "Is the South Advancing?" (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Report on Southern Literature. (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - "The Return of the Native-Introduction" (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - "Richard Croom Beatty: A Memoir" No. 1 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - " " No. 2 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - "Robert E. Lee: The Soldier" (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - " The Role of the South in Modern Literature." (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - "The Sacred Harp in the Land of Eden" (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - " " (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - "The Sacred Harp Singing at Cedar Valley" (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - "Sectionalism in America " (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - " Sectionalism in America" (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - " A Siege Gun Opens From Texas" (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - " Simms and the Critics" (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - So Red the Rose, by Stark Young-Introduction (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - " ‘ No. 1 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - " " No. 2 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - " " No. 3 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - " " Fragments (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - " Social Science Discovers Regionalism" (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - " The Sociological Proteus" (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - "A Sociologist in Eden" (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - " " (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - " Some Considerations for a Study of the Humanities" (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - " The South in Contemporary Literature" (lecture). (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - "The South and Intellectual Progress" (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - "The South and the Nation-A Historical Interpretation No. 1 (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - " " " No. 2 (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - "The Southern Agrarians" (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - " The Southern Association Joins the Kennedy Army," Coffee House Club, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - " " (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - " " (Box 27, Folder 41)
    - " " (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - "The Southern Association and Other Educational Mobs" (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - " Southern Letter" (fragment) (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - "A Southern View of Folk Song" (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - "The Southerner" (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - "The Southern Writer and the Modern University" (Box 27, Folder 47)
    - " The Statecraft of Charles A. Beard" (Box 27, Folder 48)
    - " Statement and Interpretation of the Negative" (Box 27, Folder 49)
    - Statement for Dallas Meeting, April 19 -21, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 50)
    - " Still Rebels, Still Yankees" (Box 27, Folder 51)
    - " " (Box 27, Folder 52)
    - Shenandoah (Box 27, Folder 53)
    - " Stuart's Escape and Timberlake's Mission" (Box 27, Folder 55)
    - Studies in War Time, Convocation Address, Hollins College, September 18, 1942 (Box 27, Folder 56)
    - " The Talking Oaks of the South" (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - " The Teaching of Composition and Rhetoric" (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - " The Thankless Muse and Her Fugitive Poets" (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - " Theme and Method in So Red the Rose" (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - "Theme and Method in So Red the Rose" Modern Southern Literature: A Symposium -XVII, The Hopkins Review, Spring, Summer 1953 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - " Thomas Hardy" (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Essay on Thomas Hardy, pp.2 - 12, 14 - 27 (incomplete) (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - " To the Civitans." Lecture. (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - " To Go West and South" (unfinished) (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - " To the Wardens of the Gate" (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - " The Traditional Basis of Thomas Hardy's Fiction" (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - " The Trend of Southern Literature" No. 1 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - " The Trend of Southern Literature" No. 2 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - "The Trend toward Regional Devolution" (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Tribute to Elizabeth Drew (untitled) (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - "The TVA Makes a New River" (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - "Two Schools of Southern Fiction" (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - "Two Views of the World State: Wells and A. E." (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - " The Unhappy Role of Science- 1956" (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - "Vanderbilt and the South" (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - "Vermont in Summer-Georgia in Winter" No. 1 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - " " No. 2 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - "A Very Modern Question" (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - "The Vocabulary of the Moderns" (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - " The Voyage of the Good Boat Adventure. (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - " What does History Mean? (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - "Where are the Laymen? An Inquiry into the Southern Policy Committees" (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - "Where Regionalism and Sectionalism Meet?" (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - "Where Regionalism and Sectionalism Meet?" (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - "The White Spirituals and Their Historian" (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - Whither Dixie? Mr. Barr and Mr. Ransom in the Great Debate at Richmond. (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - " Whitman and the American Spirit" (lecture) (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - " Why the Modern South has a Great Literature" (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - " William Gilmore Simms and the Southern Frontier." No. 1 (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - " " No. 2 (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - " " No. 3 (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - " Zola's Naturalism and Le Roman Experimental" (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - Untitled (address to students in American Literature class) (Box 28, Folder 38)
    - Untitled. Subject: Agrarian View of the South's Problems (Box 28, Folder 39)
    - Untitled Essay. Beginning "Americans are a Wilderness People,", 1938 (Box 28, Folder 40)
    - Untitled Essay. Subject: Civil War and the South. (Box 28, Folder 41)
    - Untitled Essay. Subject: Columbia Debate "Mr. Chairman and Fellow Tennesseans" (Box 28, Folder 42)
    - Untitled Essay. Subject: The Lack of Audience for Art in the South. (Box 28, Folder 43)
    - Untitled Essay. Subject:, Role of the Humanities in Modern Education (Box 28, Folder 44)
    - Untitled Essay. Subject: Southerners and Northerners (Box 28, Folder 45)
    - Untitled Essay. Subject: To the Kiwanis Club (Box 28, Folder 46)
    - Untitled Essay. Subject: Tribute to Dr. Sanborn (Box 28, Folder 47)
    - Davidson. Untitled essay fragments (Box 28, Folder 48)
    - Untitled Manuscripts. No. 1 (Box 28, Folder 49)
    - Untitled Manuscripts. No. 2 (Box 28, Folder 50)
    - Incomplete and fragmentary manuscripts (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - " " (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - " " (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - " " (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - " " (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Papers written while a student No. 1-"Arnold Bennett-Balanceer"; ‘Churches"; "Editorials After ‘The New Republic' "; "Meredith"; "Militarists in America"; "My Little League of Nations" (after Stephen Leacock in "Our Little Soviet, " Vanity Fair, November) (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Papers written while a student No. 2-"The Mythological and Symbolical Interpretation of Beowulf";"The Poems of Cynewulf"(term paper December 1920) (Box 29, Folder 7)